# Cherelle Simpson

Cherelle.S@hotmail.com | 07879461151 | Birmingham, UK

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/cherelle-simpson | O https://github.com/C-Sim | Portfolio: https://c-sim.github.io/portfolio/

An established business professional with extensive experience in management roles within large and reputable companies. Naturally creative and an adept problem-solver with proficiency in a wide range of coding languages and skills.

Superior attention to detail and a natural talent for internalising complex information to create an output which is digestible and aesthetically pleasing has earned me praise from high profile leaders within my past roles. As a result, I have earned opportunities to take ownership of several high-level projects which have been part of transformational business strategy.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript ES6+ | CSS3 | HTML5 | GitHub | Node.js | jQuery | Bootstrap | Moment.js | APIs | Local Storage | DOM | Bulma

## **PROJECTS**

# **Virtual Holiday**

GitHub repo https://github.com/C-Sim/virtual-holiday | Deployed URL https://c-sim.github.io/virtual-holiday/

This interactive app allows the user to experience a virtual holiday abroad. Begin by selecting a holiday type and be transported away to a new destination. Everything the user needs to recreate the holiday feeling virtually is included - from the scenery and atmospheric music, to a waiter who offers a snack and tells bad jokes.

Tools: JavaScript - jQuery - APIs - Local Storage - Video - Audio - Typewriter - DOM - CSS - HTML

# **Weather Dashboard**

GitHub repo <a href="https://github.com/C-Sim/weather-dashboard/">https://github.com/C-Sim/weather-dashboard/</a> | Deployed URL <a href="https://c-sim.github.io/weather-dashboard/">https://c-sim.github.io/weather-dashboard/</a>

A dashboard showing the current and forecast weather for a destination inputted by the user. The app retains the 6 most recent searches without duplication for easy access.

Tools: JavaScript - API - jQuery - JSON

## **Day Planner**

GitHub repo https://github.com/C-Sim/work day planner | Deployed URL https://c-sim.github.io/work day planner/

A simple calendar application that allows a user to save events for each hour of the day. The app runs in the browser and features dynamically updated HTML and CSS powered by jQuery.

Tools: JavaScript - Bootstrap - Moment.js - HTML - CSS

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Project Manager Holland & Barrett Head Office, Nuneaton | 2019 – Present

- Reporting into the Director of Change and Continuous Improvement, I have landed a number of projects across the business
  with focus on change management, efficiencies and innovation
- Managed launch of a same-day delivery service within 2 weeks as a new fulfilment channel for customers during lockdown
- Currently running projects key to the company's transformation strategy
- Key projects include: virtual customer video chat, same-day delivery, Brexit

Between these roles, I took an 8-month career break to travel, study and volunteer.

#### Revenue Development Manager National Express Head Office, Birmingham | 2017 – 2018

- Reporting into the Director of Business Development, I was responsible for the development of new and existing ancillary products totalling £15m p.a.
- Produced detailed budgets and forecasts for projected revenue, for which I was held accountable
- Delivered executive business cases for the introduction of new products, all of which were realised
- Managed complex projects to successfully introduce new digital products across multiple sales channels

# Commercial Manager National Express Head Office, Birmingham | 2015 – 2017

- Responsible for the Airport routes, which generate c.55% of the division's annual turnover £111m p.a.
- Established and maintained effective relationships with stakeholders across the business including Marketing,
   eCommerce, Service Delivery and Business Development to facilitate the success of the routes
- Built executive business cases to inform innovative pricing strategies, network changes and customer messaging

## Analyst John Lewis Head Office, London | 2013 – 2015

- Line managed the 5 members of the Pricing team and recruited new members of a high-performing team
- Conducted pricing analysis for price sensitive assortments and managed all of the business's Marketing analysis
- Influenced a variety of stakeholders to make commercial decisions which are in the best interest of the customer
- Had a full time role created as a result of the success of a data project originally requested as a one off task

## Pricing Assistant John Lewis Head Office, London | 2012 – 2013

- Became an expert on the company pricing policy, advising others on how to apply it to pricing decisions
- Contributed new ideas and processes which affected the wider business and brought positive and tangible change
- Coordinated the business's response to pricing and promotional activity within the industry

# Buying Assistant John Lewis Head Office, London | 2009 – 2012

- One quarter of a team that increased turnover by £10m within 12 months in an under-performing market
- Managed tender processes which resulted in lower costs and better service, increasing availability and margin
- Involved in producing literature, including writing copy, liaising with printers and determining pagination

# **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development | University of Birmingham, UK

- 2.1 BA (Hons), Advertising and Marketing Communications | London Metropolitan University, UK
- 4 A-levels and 12 GCSEs A\*-C | King Edwards VI Five Ways Grammar School, UK